This week has been a really crap week
for my family. And I wanted some comfort
food for me. That's ice cream,
specifically chocolate ice cream. And I
picked this up in the store. I've seen
it on the shelves for a while. Haven't
tried it and
thought I would. So, let's give this
cocoa powder a bash and make a no added
sugar ultimate chocolate ice cream with
loads of add-ins and stuff.
Yeah, I I just want chocolate ice cream.
That's kind of it. Really not going to
over complicate this video. We're just
going to get on and make it. This is
what we're going to need for this no
added sugar ultimate luxury chocolate
ice cream. You are going to need 600 g
of whipping cream, 33 36% fat. 600 g of
milk, that's whole milk. 150 gram of
alulose. 100 g of cocoa powder. Ideally
20% to 24% fat. 50 gram of dark
chocolate with no sugar added to it. 45
gram of skim milk powder and 5 g of
stevia. Now the stevia is to increase
perceived sweetness level cuz alo isn't
as sweet as sugar. So we're going to add
that in just to bring that flavor back
around. Let's get everything weighed out
and going. We're going to start off by
putting our 600 g of milk into our pan.
Straight into that, we're going to add
our alios.
That's 150 gram.
We're going to weigh out our skimm milk
paddle, which is 45 gram. I'm weighing
it into a separate container cuz I'm
going to use a stabilizer in this. It's
It's really high fat this, so you don't
need a lot. I'm going to use about 3/4
of a gram.
Uh there's that in there. Let's get a
mini whisk. Super mini whisk today.
Stirring that together to remove any
clumps of that stabilizer. I'm using my
own blend here. Um, I've mentioned it in
videos before. If you if you want to
know what it is, ask me in the comments.
So, that goes in there like that. Cocoa
powder. Again, I've seen this in stores.
Fries, an ancient brand.
I try to think how long Fries has been
around. I'm going to research it and put
it on the screen right now. We're going
to do 100 g of cocoa powder cuz I want
this
really nice strong
chocolate flavored
ice cream. So, half this pack premium
cocoa/ cacao.
Cacao is just a fancy way of saying it's
cocoa powder as opposed to drinking
chocolate. I've got one viewer that
hates that I put cocoa powder into cold
liquid. So, for that person alone,
straight into the cold liquid. And 5 g
of stevia, one teaspoon.
And the last thing we need to put in
there is our chocolate. I got all over
my hands. Which is 50 g. But for that,
get this heating up. Allow all the
ingredients to blend together. My
stabilizer needs 85
Celsius.
Sometimes I say Celsius, sometimes it's
centiggrade, which is this in
Fahrenheit. Um, and I'm going to keep it
there for 5 minutes to create a 2 to 3%
evaporation rate. By the time you get to
85 C anyway, you'll likely be around the
2% evaporation rate. So, don't stress
about it. I've got some lint chocolate,
dark chocolate.
Let's weigh. Let's weigh out 50 g. I'm
going to chop this up because when the
base is heated, I'm going to add the
chocolate in there to it. So, let's do
that. So, I've got my cream here. I've
got my chopped up chocolate. And both of
these are going to go in chocolate
first. And I got a nice cube of
chocolate to eat. There we go. 85C.
Couple of minutes. We're going to pop in
our chopped chocolate
and stir that together. That that'll
literally take about 30 seconds to a
minute for that to melt. There we go.
It's already melted. And the last thing
is our cream. And in we go with our 600
g of our cream. Obviously, this is cold
straight out the fridge. And then give
that a stir together. That cream will
bring that temperature down really nice
and fast. We're down to 41C. So nice.
[clears throat]
Wait for this to shut up.
[snorts]
>> [snorts]
>> And we're going to pop that in a
container.
If you want to cool this down over an
ice bath, can't talk. Ice bath, then by
all means do. I absolutely can't be
bothered. Straight in the fridge
and then we'll come back tomorrow
morning. So, with the base out of the
fridge, we're going to give it a good
stir before we put it in our pre-chilled
machine. This will also work in the
Ninja Creamy, obviously. And whilst
that's chilling, [music] we're going to
get some these are Costco two white
brownies. Really nice fudgy brownies.
and some of this. This is that condensed
milk fudge. I'll put links in the
description for this as well. Chopped up
into small pieces. And this is leftover
fudge swirl from another video. It's all
going in here today. So, that's kind of
warmed up and stirred, ready to go. And
we're going to start loading up the
tubs. [music]
Mix it all in together. This is just
going to be delicious. It smells
incredible already. So, let's put
everything in, then put it in the
freezer to go completely hard.
So, So for me, comfort ice cream is or
comfort food is ice cream. Uh I like
dense chocolate ice cream with add-ins,
fudge brownies, chocolate flex, all that
kind of stuff. That's my comfort ice
cream. This is a high solids chocolate
ice cream because we've added that extra
chocolate. The chocolate increases the
solids, the physical chocolate increases
the solids. So it scoops a little bit
harder even when you balance it to -4
because the solids content is high. So
technically the ice cream is the same
consistency, but the solids make it a
slightly higher density,
but it means that you can sit there with
the tub, not worry about it turning into
liquid before you finished it. So here
we are on Thursday
at 8:22 in the morning
and I'm going to eat delicious chocolate
ice cream.
I've used Costco two bite brownies in
this. Normal like two bite brownies from
Safeway, supermarket, whatever. They
don't seem to have the same texture.
They're a little bit lighter, but they
still work really well in ice cream. The
Costco ones are a little bit denser.
They're a little more chewy. So, when
you put them in ice cream, you get, for
me personally, you get a much better
kind of texture. It's It's frozen and
chewy and delicious. Those pieces,
little flexcks of fudge in there. Also
delicious. I mean, that fudge has been
in the freezer for
6 months, maybe even more. And we've got
that fudge swirl in there. I will put
links in the description
to videos you can get the recipes for
the hard fudge and the soft fudge
and go from there. But I just really
fancied this ice cream this week. I know
I said I would do the soft serve, but I
will now I will do that next week. I
promise. Thank you everyone for liking
and subscribing and I will see you next
week when I will actually do soft serve
ice cream in that Gouria soft serve
machine. So until then, see you later.